A Guide to the Publications of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1947-1997
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Studies in Bibliography
  - (1957); Decennial Extra Volume; also issued as Rudolph Hirsch, Howell J. Heaney, Fredson Bowers, and Lucy Clark, Selective Check Lists of Bibliographical Scholarship, 1949-1955. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1957. viii, 192 pp., 10
    . "The check lists are divided into two sections. `Part I: Incunabula and Early Renaissance' has been compiled from the start by Rudolph Hirsch of the University of Pennsylvania. `Part II: Later Renaissance to the Present' has been edited by Howell J. Heaney of the Free Library of Philadelphia, with the single exception of the section for the 1949 check list which was the work of Mr. Bowers and Lucy Clark of the University of Virginia Library. The present volume contains photo offset reprints of the first six check lists, for the years 1949-1954, originally bound in Studies in Volumes III through VIII, and the first printing of the check list for 1955, which did not appear in Volume IX.... To make the seven check lists in this volume of more service to the user, an index was prepared [by Anne Freudenberg] at the instigation of the Secretary of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia.... The index also includes the notation of articles from Studies in Bibliography.. ., Volume I, which appeared prior to the contents of the first check list, and for articles from Volume IX" (Preface, by Anne Freudenberg). Blue boards. Separate issue: As
    Selective Check Lists... 1949-1955
    (with first paragraph of Preface revised). Some copies, apparently intended to complete sets of
    Studies
    after volume 10 had sold out, have a slip laid in that is printed in red and reads: "Volume X / The
    Selective Check Lists of Bibliographical Scholarship
    1949-1955 was prepared as a 10th anniversary volume and it differs somewhat in content and format from the other
    . In spite of the oblique note on the copyright page ["This is a separate issue of sheets from Volume X of
    . "] this is the complete Volume X of the series and should be catalogued as such." Red boards. 756 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1958). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1958. [4], 297, [1] pp., 11
    "Volume Eleven of the Society's Papers,
    , was produced at the University of Virginia Press. Linotype, Baskerville 11, 10, and 8 point, leaded, was employed. Headings were set in 18 point Kennerley. The volume was bound by Charles H. Bohn of New York City. One thousand copies were manufactured on Strathmore Pastelle text stock." Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, February 1966. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 269-290), business information (p. 293), and publications lists (pp. 296-297) omitted. 551 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1959). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1959. [4], 260 pp., 12
    Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, February 1966. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 234-254), business information (p. 257), and publications lists (p. 260) omitted. 570 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1960). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1960. [6], 290 pp., 13
    Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, February 1966. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 262-283), business information (p. 287), and publications lists (p. 290) omitted. 569 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1961). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1961. [4], 291 pp., 14
    Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, February 1966. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 263-284), business information (p. 288), and publications lists (p. 291) omitted. 538 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1962). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1962. [8], 311, [1] pp., 15
    "Volume fifteen of the Society's Papers,
    , was produced at the University of Virginia Press. Linotype Baskerville, 11, 10, 9, and 8 point, leaded, was employed. Headings were set in 18 point Baskerville No. 2. The volume was bound by Charles H. Bohn of New York City. Fourteen hundred copies were manufactured on 80 pound Standard Permalife Text." Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, January 1970. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 279-305), Forthcoming Publications (p. 311), and Colophon (p. 312) omitted. 573 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1963). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1963. [4], 276 pp., 16
    Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, June 1972. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 245-270) and publications lists (p. 276) omitted. 500 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1964). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1964. [6], 258 pp., 17
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office. Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, October 1969. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 229-252), Garner correction (p. 252), and Forthcoming Publications (p. 258) omitted. Presswork by Valley Offset, Deposit, N.Y. 554 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1965). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1965. [6], 312, [1] pp., 18
    "Volume eighteen of the Society's Papers,
    , was produced at the University of Virginia Printing Office. Linotype Baskerville 11, 10, 9, and 8 point, leaded, was employed. Headings were set in 18 point Baskerville No. 2. The volume was bound by Charles H. Bohn of New York City. Fourteen hundred copies were manufactured on 80 pound Strathmore Pastelle Text." Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia and University Press of Virginia, October 1969. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 283-306), Forthcoming Publications (p. 312), and Colophon (p. 313) omitted. Presswork by Valley Offset, Deposit, N.Y. 570 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1966). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1966. [6], 282 pp., 19
    Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia & University Press of Virginia, January 1968. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 251-275), business information (279-280), and publications list (281) omitted. Presswork by Valley Offset, Deposit, N.Y. 601 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1967); Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1967. [6], 298 pp., 20
    Binding by Kingsport Press, Kingsport, Tenn.; collotype plate facing p. 26 by L Van Leer & Co NV, Amsterdam. Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia & University Press of Virginia, July 1968 ("with corrections"). Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 274-291), business information (295), and publications list (298) omitted. Presswork by Valley Offset, Deposit, N.Y. 657 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1968); Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1968. [6], 290 pp., 21
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office. 1500 copies. Reprint: Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia & University Press of Virginia, January 1970. Glassine dust jacket. Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship (pp. 267-284) omitted. 536 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1969). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1969. [6], 341 pp., 22
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office; binding by Kingsport Press, Kingsport, Tenn. 2000 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1970). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1970. [4], 280 pp., 23
    Composition and presswork (using 80 pound Strathmore Pastelle Text) by University of Virginia Printing Office; binding by Kingsport Press, Kingsport, Tenn. 2000 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1971). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1971. [4], 240 pp., 24
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office; plates by Meriden Gravure. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1972); as Studies in Bibliography (dropping the sub- title present since vol. 2). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1972. [4], 252 pp., 25
    ?2200 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1973). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1973. [4], 296 pp., 26
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office; binding by Complete Books, Philadelphia. ?2200 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1974). Fredson Bowers, Editor; L. A. Beaurline, Associate Editor; Gillian Kyles, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1974. [4], 325 pp., 27
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office; binding by Complete Books, Philadelphia. 2059 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1975). Fredson Bowers, Editor; Gillian Kyles and Clinton Sisson, Assistants to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1975. [6], 339, [1] pp., 28
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office; binding by Complete Books, Philadelphia. 2054 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1976). Fredson Bowers, Editor; Gillian Kyles and Clinton Sisson, Assistants to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1976. [4], 395 pp., 29
    Composition and presswork by University of Virginia Printing Office. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1977). Fredson Bowers, Editor; Susan Hitchcock, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1977. [4], 286 pp., 30
  - (1978). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1978. [6], 273, [4] pp., 31
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 2033 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1979). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1979. [6], 285, [5] pp., 32
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 2028 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1980). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1980. [6], 282 pp., 33
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1996 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1981). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1981. [6], 276, [1] pp., 34
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1999 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1982). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1982. [6], 338, [1] pp., 35
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 2007 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1983). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1983. [6], 272 pp., 36
  - (1984). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1984. [6], 312 pp., 37
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1995 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1985). Fredson Bowers, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1985. [4], 380 pp., 38
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1495 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1986). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David Vander Meulen, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1986. [6], 303 pp., 39
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1297 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1987). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David L. Vander Meulen, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1987. [6], 236 pp., 40
    Composition and printing, on 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, by Heritage Printers, Charlotte, N.C. 1306 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1988). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David Vander Meulen, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1988. [6], 329, [1] pp., 41
    "This book was printed by letterpress from type cast on the Linotype by Heritage Printers, Inc. of Charlotte, North Carolina. The typeface is Baskerville, a design by John Baskerville (1706-1775), English printer and typefounder. Linotype Baskerville is a weight-for-weight and curve-for-curve copy of Baskerville's celebrated printing type. The pattern for the cutting was a complete font of (approximately) 14 point, cast from Baskerville's own matrices exhumed at Paris, France, in 1929. The paper is 70-pound Warren's Olde Style, an acid-free paper with a useful life of 300 years." 1380 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1989). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David L. Vander Meulen, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1989. [6], 306, [1] pp., 42
    "This book was printed by letterpress from type cast on the Linotype by Heritage Printers, Inc. of Charlotte, North Carolina. The typeface is Baskerville, a design by John Baskerville (1706-1775), English printer and typefounder. Linotype Baskerville is a weight-for-weight and curve-for-curve copy of Baskerville's celebrated printing type. The pattern for the cutting was a complete font of (approximately) 14 point, cast from Baskerville's own matrices exhumed at Paris, France, in 1929. The paper is 70-pound Glatfelter, an acid-free paper with a useful life of 300 years." 1211 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1990). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David L. Vander Meulen, Assistant Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1990. [6], 292 [1] pp., 43
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1203 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1991). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David L. Vander Meulen, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1991. [6], 386, [1] pp., 44
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1216 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1992). Fredson Bowers, Editor; David L. Vander Meulen, Associate Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1992. [8], 338 [1] pp., 45
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1235 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1993). David L. Vander Meulen, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1993. [6], 388, [1] pp., 46
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1113 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1994). David L. Vander Meulen, Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1994. [6], 272, [1] pp., 47
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1011 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1995). David L. Vander Meulen, Editor; Elizabeth K. Lynch, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1995. viii, 305, [2] pp., 48
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 991 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1996). David L. Vander Meulen, Editor; Elizabeth K. Lynch, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1996. [6], 300, [1] pp., 49
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1058 copies. Electronic edition: see 1997.3.
  - (1997). David L. Vander Meulen, Editor; Elizabeth K. Lynch, Assistant to the Editor. Charlottesville: For Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia by University Press of Virginia, 1997. [6], 416, [1] pp., 50
    Colophon as for vol. 42. 1000 copies.
- Separate Publications
  - (Bowers, Fredson. Description of the Six Impressions of Washington Irving's Woolfert's [sic] Roost. [Ch, 1947.] 6 pp., 1947.1
    No covering. "Mimeographed to illustrate a talk by Fredson Bowers before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, February 26, 1947, on the description of modern books." Summarized in, and distributed to members with,
    1 (Mar. 1947).)
  - Hinman, Charlton. "Why 79 First Folios?" [Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1947.] 12 pp., 1947.2
    Mimeographed; no covering. "A Paper read before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, June 6, 1947." Distributed to members with
    3 (June 1947).
  - Norfolk Copyright Entries, 1837, 1851-3, 1856-7, 1858-9, 1864, 1866-71. Registers of Copyrights and Copies of the Court Records for Copyrights of the Federal District Court at Norfolk, Virginia, Generally Referred to as the Court of the Eastern District of Virginia. Transcribed by Barbara Harris with some notes by John Wyllie. Charlottesville: Mimeographed for Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1947. 48 pp., 1947.3
    Mimeographed; no covering.
  - Fischer, Earl K. Printing Ink. [Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1948.] 14 pp., 2 illus., 1948.1
    Mimeographed; no covering. "An address before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, November 17, 1947."
  - Miller, C. William. Henry Herringman. [Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1948.] 13 pp., 1948.2
    Mimeographed; no covering. "A paper read before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, February 13, 1948."
  - (Black, Robert. The Sadleir-Black Gothic Collection. Charlottesville: Published by the University of Virginia Library, 1949. 15 pp. (incl. both sides of front cover)., 1949.1
    Stiff paper covers. "An address before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia [on May 12, 1949]." Includes Michael Sadleir's "own account of the formation of the collection." One of the "Mimeographed Papers Distributed by the Society in 1949" (
    2).)
  - Bowers, Fredson. A Supplement to the Woodward & McManaway Check List of English Plays 1641-1700. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1949. 22 pp., 1949.2
    Mimeographed; stiff paper covers.
  - Miller, C. William. Henry Herringman Imprints: A Preliminary Checklist. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1949. [2], 50 pp., 1949.3
  - Wolf, Edwin, 2nd. The Textual Importance of Manuscript Commonplace Books of 1620-1660. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1949. 24 pp., 1949.4
    Mimeographed; stiff paper covers. "An address before the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia January 14, 1949."
  - Wyllie, John Cook. Preliminary Finding List of Writings on the Kentucky Book Trade. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1949. 7 pp., 1949.5
    Mimeographed; no covering. "Compiled under the auspices of the Committee on 19th Century Publishers [footnote: "... John Cook Wyllie (Chairman for Southeastern States)'] of the American Bibliographical Society."
  - Day, Cyrus L. Dates and Performances of Thomas D'Urfey's Plays. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1950. 24 pp., 1950.1
  - Fishwick, Marshall W. A Bibliography of the American Hero. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1950. 16 pp., 1950.2
  - Morrison, Paul. Index of Printers, Publishers and Booksellers in A. W. Pollard and G. R. Redgrave A Short-Title Catalogue of Books Printed in England, Scotland & Ireland and of English Books Printed Abroad 1475- 1640. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1950. [2], 82, [1] pp., 1950.3
    Stiff paper wrappers; a "near-print publication." 750 copies. A leaf "Addenda & Corrigenda To Morrison's STC Index, as reported up to the date of publication" laid in; "Further Addenda and Corrigenda will be reported by the Secretary of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia in the Society's
    [see
    27 (July 1953) and corrected reprint, 1961.4]."
  - Stephens, Robert F. A Check List of Masters' Theses on Edmund Spenser. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1950. 16 pp., 1950.4
  - Verner, Coolie. A Further Checklist of the Separate Editions of Jefferson's Notes on the State of Virginia. Charlottesville: Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, 1950. 26 pp. (incl. front cover)., 1950.5